Okay, so
I did change a little bit between the
last video and this video. And the thing
I changed is I added some styling. So um
if we come over here, we can say hello
hello world
close. And if we click show modal, the
modal pops up and we can click close. So
nothing that I did there, nothing has
changed except the styling. Just wanted
to show you that everything is exactly
the same. What would be really nice is
if I could make it so that this box was
automatically selected as soon as they
clicked close mo close close. So if I
click show modal, it shows when I click
close, nothing is selected. And it'd be
really nice if my cursor automatically
went into this text box. So I'm going to
show you how to do that. The way you do
that is you'd say document doquery
selector and then you look for the
element you're trying to target. And in
this case, I'm trying to target the
element with the title ID. And then what
I want to do is I want to focus that
element. What it does is it puts the
focus of the page onto that element. And
so now I can enter a title. Say hello
hello world
and close. And if I click show modal,
the modal pops up. When I click close,
my cursor automatically goes into that
text box, which is pretty dang cool. But
um there are so many things that you can
do with JavaScript. Once you are able to
target an element in your HTML page,
there are so many things you can do to
that element. And to look it up, what
I'd do is I would Google search and I
would look for element
methods and then probably put HTML on
the end. And when you do, it'll give you
uh this is one. Oh, wrong one. This is
one I've used and it shows you all of
the things that you can do. And there's
just so many things you could do. So,
for example, on an element, you could
convert it to a string. Um, you could
set attribute. These are some that I've
shown you before. Um, you could, um, get
its outer HTML. Uh, you could get the
last child. Um, you could get the inner
text. Um, and there's so many things you
could do. There's the focus I just
showed you, and I encourage you to look
into a few of these. Um, the other place
that's really good to look is MDN web
docs. They have a whole bunch of stuff
here and good documentation. And if
you're willing to read through a little
bit of technical terminology, they are
really good. Um, and that concludes this
video. Thanks for watching.